Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we're going to be talking about a very fun game.
我是Catherine，今天我们要聊一个非常有趣的游戏。
That's right.
没错。
Today we're going bowling, a very popular sport amongst many people and so we're going
今天我们要去打保龄球，这是一项很多人喜欢的运动，所以我们要
to take a look at how you play this sport and all the vocab related to this great game.
看看怎么玩这项运动，以及所有和这个精彩游戏相关的词汇。
Alright so let's take a listen to our dialogue and we'll be right back.
好了，我们先听一下对话，马上回来。
Alright, so the first thing you need to know about bowling is that you should never cross
好的，关于保龄球，你首先要知道的是，你绝对不能越过
that line where the lane begins.
球道开始的那条线。
Why not?
为什么不能？
Because they polish and oil it to make the ball slide down.
因为他们给球道打蜡上油，让球能滑过去。
If you step there you'll slip and fall.
如果你踩上去，会滑倒摔跤的。
Okay so I got my bowling shoes, my ball, our names on the scorecard, so now how the heck
好吧，我穿上了保龄球鞋，拿了球，记分卡上也有我们的名字，那我到底怎么
do I play this?
玩这个啊？
You throw the ball down the lane and try to knock down all the pins.
你把球扔到球道上，试着击倒所有的球瓶。
If you do, that is called a strike.
如果你做到了，那就叫全中。
If you don't knock them all down on the first try, then you get a chance to get the spare.
如果第一次没全部击倒，你还有机会补中。
After 10 frames we add up the points and see who has the most.
打完十局后，我们算总分，看谁最高。
300 is a perfect score but very hard to get.
300分是满分，但很难拿到。
Got it.
明白了。
Okay I'm going to give it a go.
好，我来试试看。
Oh no, my ball went in the gutter.
哦不，我的球掉进沟里了。
I told you, it's harder than you think.
我告诉过你，这比你想的难。
Now let a pro show you how it's done.
现在让专业人士给你示范一下怎么打。
Alright we're back so now let's take a look at some of that vocab on Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了，现在来看看“语言学习”环节里的词汇。
So the first word we have today in Language Takeaway is lane.
今天“语言学习”的第一个词是“球道”。
That's right, a bowling lane.
没错，保龄球球道。
So a lane, that is where you actually play this game.
球道，就是你实际玩这个游戏的地方。
That's right a lane is also a word for like a road, a small narrow road.
对，“lane”这个词也可以指像路一样的东西，一条窄窄的小路。
So in bowling this is the flat surface, the floor that's long that you roll the ball down.
在保龄球里，这就是那个平坦的表面，长长的地板，你把球滚过去。
That's right, okay so that's your lane.
没错，那就是你的球道。
So as you said you roll the ball down the lane and you try to knock down the pins that
就像你说的，你把球滚下球道，试着击倒
are at the end of the lane.
球道尽头的球瓶。
That's right so pins are, they're a little bit heavy, they're usually white and they
对，球瓶就是，它们有点重，通常是白色的，而且
have, they're wide at the bottom and narrow at the top.
底部宽、顶部窄。
They almost look like wine bottles.
它们看起来几乎像酒瓶。
And the goal of the game is to knock these down, to make them fall on the ground.
游戏的目标就是击倒它们，让它们倒在地上。
That's right, okay so that's why you are using, that's why you are throwing the ball down
没错，所以这就是为什么你要用，为什么你要把球扔下
the lane to knock down these pins.
球道去击倒这些球瓶。
Now if you knock all of them down on your first try, that's called a strike.
如果你第一次尝试就全部击倒，那叫全中。
A strike, that's right.
全中，没错。
So that means all ten pins fall down on your first try.
也就是说，你第一次尝试就把所有十个球瓶都击倒了。
But sometimes you don't get a strike, you maybe knock down eight pins and then later
但有时候你打不出全中，你可能击倒了八个球瓶，然后
on your second try, because every person gets two tries, on your second try you knock down
第二次尝试时，因为每个人有两次机会，你第二次击倒了
the last two pins.
最后两个球瓶。
Now what's that called Marco?
那叫什么，Marco？
So if you knock all of them down on your second try, that's called a spare.
如果你第二次尝试全部击倒，那叫补中。
Okay strike, usually you write it with an X, that's on the scorecard and a spare, which
好，全中，通常用X表示，写在记分卡上；补中，也就是
is two tries to get all ten pins, that's a slash.
两次尝试击倒所有十个球瓶，用斜线表示。
That's right.
没错。
A spare.
补中。
And if you don't get all of the pins in two tries, you still get points.
如果你两次尝试没击倒所有球瓶，你还是有得分。
So if you knock down eight pins, you get eight.
所以如果你击倒了八个球瓶，就得八分。
Or if you knock down four pins, you get four.
或者如果你击倒了四个球瓶，就得四分。
That's right.
没错。
And you put your score on your scorecard and now each player usually gets ten frames or
你把分数记在记分卡上，每个玩家通常有十局，也就是
ten different opportunities to knock down all the pins.
十次不同的机会去击倒所有球瓶。
Alright so usually these are boxes on the scorecard and you can play ten frame bowling
好，这些通常是记分卡上的格子，你可以打十局保龄球
or also five frame.
或者五局。
But it's important to remember that each frame gives you the opportunity to bowl two times.
但重要的是要记住，每局给你两次投球的机会。
Right.
对。
Alright so you get those two tries.
好，所以你有两次尝试。
So really it's twenty total tries to knock down these pins.
所以实际上总共有二十次尝试去击倒这些球瓶。
That's right.
没错。
And now if you did really well and on every opportunity of each frame, you got a strike,
如果你打得很好，每局的每次机会都打出全中，
that means that you would get a perfect score.
那就意味着你会得到满分。
That's right a perfect score, that means that you made no mistakes, you knocked down all
对，满分，就是说你没有失误，第一次尝试就击倒了所有
the pins on the first try.
球瓶。
And now obviously down the lane, it's not as easy as it looks because to the sides of
显然，在球道上，这并不像看起来那么容易，因为在你球道的
your bowling lane, you have this kind of a path that's to the bottom.
两侧，有这种通向底部的通道。
So if your ball goes in there, you can't get it out.
所以如果你的球滚进去，就拿不出来了。
That's right.
没错。
So remember like I said earlier, a lane is also the name of a place where we can walk
记住，就像我之前说的，“lane”也可以指我们走路
or drive.
或开车的地方。
It's like a road.
就像一条路。
Well we have gutters which are on the sides of these roads and also in bowling gutters.
我们有“gutter”（排水沟），在道路两侧，保龄球里也有“gutter”。
They're lower and normally on the streets, they're for water but in bowling, they're
它们更低，通常在街上，是用来排水的，但在保龄球里，它们是
the places on the right or the left side where your ball will fall.
你球道右侧或左侧，球会掉进去的地方。
And if your ball falls into the gutter or it rolls into the gutter, you will hit no
如果你的球掉进沟里，或者滚进沟里，你就一个球瓶
pins.
都打不中。
Right.
没错。
I think that's the main thing.
我觉得这是主要的事情。
If your ball goes in the gutter, you don't hit any pins at all.
如果你的球掉进球沟，你就一个球瓶都打不中。
It just goes straight down and you don't hit anything.
它就直接滚下去，你什么也打不到。
That's right.
没错。
So it's really sad when you bowl badly and you get a gutter ball we call it.
所以当你打得不好，得到一个我们称之为“球沟球”时，真的很郁闷。
That's right.
没错。
All right, so let's take a look at all this vocab again.
好了，那我们再来看看这些词汇。
Let's listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a bit with Fluency Builder.
我们来听一下对话，稍后我们会回来进行流利度训练。
All right.
好的。
So the first thing you need to know about bowling is that you should never cross that
关于保龄球，你首先需要知道的是，你绝不能越过
line where the lane begins.
球道开始的那条线。
Why not?
为什么不能？
Because they polish and oil it to make the ball slide down.
因为他们会打磨和上油，让球滑下去。
If you step there, you'll slip and fall.
如果你踩到那里，你会滑倒摔跤。
Okay.
好的。
So I got my bowling shoes, my ball, our names on the scorecard.
所以我拿到了我的保龄球鞋、我的球，记分牌上还有我们的名字。
So now how the heck do I play this?
那么现在我到底该怎么玩呢？
You throw the ball down the lane and try to knock down all the pins.
你把球扔到球道上，试着击倒所有球瓶。
If you do, that is called a strike.
如果你做到了，那就叫“全中”。
If you don't knock them all down on the first try, then you get a chance to get the spare.
如果第一次没全部击倒，你就有机会补中。
After 10 frames, we add up the points and see who has the most.
十局之后，我们加起来分数，看谁最高。
300 is a perfect score, but very hard to get.
300分是满分，但很难拿到。
Got it.
明白了。
Okay.
好的。
I'm going to give it a go.
我来试试看。
Oh no.
哦不。
My ball went in the gutter.
我的球掉进球沟了。
I told you.
我告诉过你。
It's harder than you think.
这比你想象的要难。
Now let a pro show you how it's done.
现在让专业人士给你示范一下怎么做。
All right.
好的。
So we've picked out three different phrases for you.
所以我们为你挑选了三个不同的短语。
Let's take a look at those now in Fluency Builder.
现在我们在流利度训练中来看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
All right.
好的。
So the first phrase that we have today is something that you're going to hear a lot,
今天我们第一个短语是你经常会听到的，
although I want to remind everyone this is very informal.
不过我想提醒大家，这非常不正式。
So we heard someone say in the dialogue, so now how the heck do I play this?
我们在对话中听到有人说：“那么现在我到底该怎么玩呢？”
Okay.
好的。
So how the heck do I turn this computer on?
那么我到底该怎么打开这台电脑呢？
Okay.
好的。
So how do I turn this computer on means I don't know, please help me.
“我该怎么打开这台电脑”意思是“我不知道，请帮帮我”。
But how the heck means I really don't know.
但“到底该怎么”意思是“我真的不知道”。
I really need your help.
我真的需要你的帮助。
That's right.
没错。
I really don't understand what's going on.
我真的不明白发生了什么。
I need someone's help.
我需要有人帮忙。
Like how the heck did this happen means I absolutely did not expect this to happen.
比如“这到底是怎么发生的”意思是“我完全没预料到会发生这种事”。
I'm very surprised.
我非常惊讶。
That's right.
没错。
It's actually a not very polite phrase to use, but at the same time, it's not terribly
这其实是一个不太礼貌的短语，但与此同时，它也不是特别
in plight.
冒犯。
It's in the middle.
它处于中间位置。
But it's very informal.
但它非常不正式。
All right.
好的。
So now the person understands how to bowl, how the game works, and he says, okay, got
现在这个人明白了怎么打保龄球，游戏怎么玩，他说：“好的，明白
it.
了。”
I'm going, I'm gonna give it a go.
我要去，我要去试试看。
Okay.
好的。
I'm gonna means I'm going to, and this is very informal.
“I'm gonna”意思是“I'm going to”，这非常不正式。
Gonna is a way to say going to, I will.
“Gonna”是“going to”的一种说法，意思是“我将要”。
But the phrase here is give it a go.
但这里的短语是“give it a go”。
What does that mean, Marco?
那是什么意思，Marco？
Give it a go.
“Give it a go”。
So if you're gonna give it a go, it means that you're going to try.
所以如果你要“give it a go”，意思是你打算尝试一下。
Okay.
好的。
So I'm gonna try.
所以我要试试。
So we could say this.
所以我们可以这么说。
Now that we know how to play the game, let's give it a go.
既然我们知道怎么玩这个游戏了，让我们试试看。
Let's try to play because we've been talking about it, but we haven't been doing it.
让我们试着玩一下，因为我们一直在谈论它，但还没真正玩过。
That's right.
没错。
To give it a go means to try to do something.
“To give it a go”意思是尝试做某事。
Exactly.
完全正确。
And that's basically it.
基本上就是这样。
If maybe you're watching a game on the street and you want to try maybe a card game, you
如果你在街上看到有人在玩游戏，你想试试，比如纸牌游戏，你
say, okay, I want to give it a go.
就说：“好的，我想试试看。”
I want to give it a go.
我想试试看。
All right.
好的。
And what about our last phrase?
那我们最后一个短语呢？
Now the very last phrase is the last phrase of our dialogue.
现在最后一个短语是我们对话的最后一句。
The character says, now let a pro show you how it's done.
角色说，现在让专业人士给你演示一下怎么做。
All right.
好的。
So how it's done, this let me show you how it's done, because this person is saying,
所以“how it's done”，这个“让我给你演示怎么做”，因为这个人是在说，
I'm a pro.
我是专业人士。
Let me show you how it's done.
让我给你演示怎么做。
It's a very interesting way of saying something in English.
这是英语中一种很有趣的表达方式。
What is the real meaning of this phrase?
这个短语的真正含义是什么？
He's basically saying, now let me show you how to do it.
他基本上是在说，现在让我给你演示怎么做。
Okay, the correct way.
好的，正确的方法。
Right.
对。
So basically he's saying, you didn't do it very well.
所以他基本上是在说，你做得不太好。
You didn't bowl very well.
你保龄球打得不太好。
You're new.
你是新手。
Let me show you how professional people bowl.
让我给你演示专业人士怎么打保龄球。
Right.
对。
Let me give you an example.
我给你举个例子。
Exactly.
没错。
Maybe you and your friend are making a cake and you don't really know what you're doing.
也许你和朋友在做蛋糕，但你不太清楚自己在做什么。
So your friend says, move over.
所以你的朋友会说，让开。
Let me show you how it's done.
让我给你演示怎么做。
That means the proper way to do it, the correct way.
那意味着正确的方法，恰当的方式。
So Marco, you're not doing it right.
所以Marco，你做得不对。
Let me show you how it's done.
让我给你演示怎么做。
Exactly.
没错。
A very useful phrase.
一个非常有用的短语。
And actually it can seem a little bit confusing because you're using the verb there, done.
实际上它可能有点让人困惑，因为你用了动词“done”。
So it may seem a little bit weird, do, done.
所以可能看起来有点奇怪，“do, done”。
But don't worry about it.
但别担心。
Just take it as a phrase.
就把它当作一个短语来记。
Let me show you how to do it.
让我给你演示怎么做。
Let me show you how it's done.
That's right.
没错。
So that's all we've got for Fluency Builder today.
这就是今天Fluency Builder的全部内容。
Just take another listen to our dialogue and we'll be back in a second.
再听一遍我们的对话，我们马上回来。
All right.
好的。
So the first thing you need to know about bowling is that you should never cross that
所以关于保龄球，你首先需要知道的是，你绝不能越过
line where the lane begins.
球道开始的那条线。
Why not?
为什么不能？
Because they polish and oil it to make the ball slide down.
因为他们给球道打蜡上油，让球滑下去。
If you step there, you'll slip and fall.
如果你踩到那里，你会滑倒摔跤。
Okay.
好的。
So I got my bowling shoes, my ball, our names on the scorecard.
所以我有了保龄球鞋、球，还有记分牌上的名字。
So now how the heck do I play this?
那么现在我到底该怎么玩呢？
You throw the ball down the lane and try to knock down all the pins.
你把球扔到球道上，试着击倒所有球瓶。
If you do, that is called a strike.
如果你做到了，那叫全中。
If you don't knock them all down in the first try, then you get a chance to get the spare.
如果第一次没全部击倒，你就有机会补中。
After 10 frames, we add up the points and see who has the most.
十局之后，我们加起来分数，看谁最高。
300 is a perfect score, but very hard to get.
300分是满分，但很难拿到。
Got it.
明白了。
Okay.
好的。
I'm going to give it a go.
我来试试看。
Oh, no.
哦，不。
My ball went in the gutter.
我的球掉进沟里了。
I told you.
我告诉过你。
It's harder than you think.
这比你想的要难。
Now let a pro show you how it's done.
现在让专业人士给你演示怎么做。
All right.
好的。
We're back.
我们回来了。
So bowling is actually a very, kind of like a pastime in the United States.
所以保龄球在美国其实是一种消遣活动。
You get together with friends and you just go bowling.
你和朋友聚在一起，就去打保龄球。
That's right.
没错。
I do believe it's also considered a sport.
我确实认为它也被视为一项运动。
So many people play professionally or semi-professionally.
所以很多人专业或半专业地玩。
But for me, it's always been a very social game, something you do with a group of friends.
但对我来说，它一直是一种社交游戏，是和一群朋友一起做的事。
You go out.
你出去。
It's really fun.
真的很有趣。
Yeah.
是啊。
And especially because when you go bowling, many people can play, right?
特别是因为去打保龄球时，很多人可以一起玩，对吧？
Not obviously at the same time, but you take turns.
当然不是同时，而是轮流。
And so while you're waiting, people are talking and eating.
所以在等待的时候，人们聊天、吃东西。
So it is a very social activity.
所以这是一种非常社交的活动。
That's right.
没错。
So maybe a group of people will rent a lane.
所以可能一群人会租一条球道。
Remember, we were talking earlier about a lane being that one kind of strip of wood
记得我们之前说过，球道就是那种木条
where you roll the ball.
你滚球的地方。
Well, a group of friends can rent a lane or two lanes and the four or the eight of you
嗯，一群朋友可以租一条或两条球道，你们四个人或八个人
can play together, each person playing one frame at a time.
可以一起玩，每人一次打一局。
That's right.
没错。
And now actually, the other thing about it is it's very funny to see people trying to
而且实际上，另一件事是，看到人们尝试时很有趣。
bowl or maybe with the heavy ball or maybe they pass the line that we said they shouldn't
用保龄球或者重球，或者他们越过了我们说不该越过的线
pass and they slip and fall.
然后滑倒摔跤。
So I guess that's what also makes it a little bit fun to play.
所以我觉得这也是让这项运动有点好玩的地方。
Yes, it can be a little bit embarrassing if you're not...
是的，如果你不太擅长，可能会有点尴尬……
I'm not very good, so I'm a very embarrassing bowler.
我不太擅长，所以我是个很尴尬的保龄球手。
But it's also really fun because if you go and you just have a nice time, it's a very
但这也很有趣，因为如果你去玩，好好享受时光，它是一项非常
social game.
社交性的游戏。
Well, it is.
嗯，确实如此。
And actually, we are really curious to know if you've ever been bowling.
实际上，我们很好奇你有没有打过保龄球。
I know many people who've never been bowling and they find it very, very fun.
我知道很多人从没打过保龄球，但他们觉得非常非常有趣。
So why don't you come to our website EnglishPod.com and leave your questions and comments there
所以不如来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，留下你的问题和评论
as well.
吧。
Yeah, we hope to see you there.
是啊，希望在那里见到你。
Until next time, guys.
下次再见，各位。
Thanks for watching EnglishPod.
感谢收看 EnglishPod。